<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Backtestd documentation</title>
    <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Backtestd documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding new Indicators</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/adding-new-indicators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/adding-new-indicators/</guid>
      <description>Indicator Definitions The Indicators descriptions are defined with yaml config files in the config directory. /nnfx/config/indicator/{function}/{indicator}.yaml
The function of the indicator referres to it&amp;rsquo;s function within the algorithm. Like confirmation, exit, baseline, &amp;hellip;
Example config for ASH:
name:ashfilename:ASHclass:ZeroLineCrossinputs:- - 9.0- 4.0- 20.0- 1.0- - 2.0- 0.0- 10.0- 1.0- - 0.0- 0.0- 1.0- 1.0- - 0.0- 0.0- 3.0- 1.0- - 0.0- 0.0- 6.0- 1.0buffers:- 0shift:0   option description     name The Name of the indicator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/algorithm/</guid>
      <description>:CUSTOM_ID: algorithm
An algorithm in this system defines the rules on how to combine the Signals form various Indicators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithm Rules</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/algorithm-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/algorithm-rules/</guid>
      <description>:ID: 3d2f35ed-3bb2-49c2-80be-209caf62b56c
Algorithm Rules The algorithm rules describe how the signals of individual indicators are combined to make a trading decision.
The rules describe a signaling indicator and multiple filter indicators. The signaling indicator gives a signal and if the filter indicators agree to this signal, a new trade may be opened.
Indicators at the confirmation, baseline and continuation function act as signaling indicators. All other indicators act as a filter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Results</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/analyzing-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/analyzing-results/</guid>
      <description>When backtesting indicators or indicator sets there is a significant likelihood of curve fitting which gives good results for the specific backtested period but would not give good results in forward testing. This is also called over-optimization.
Filtering Over-Optimization Parameter Optimization describes that if the value of a Continuous Input changes, the result value must change proportionally to the input change.
Assumtion: based on Parameter Optimization
If the value of a continuous input changes by a single step but the result changes significantly, the results can be considered random and must be filtered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Average True Range (ATR)</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/average-true-range-atr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/average-true-range-atr/</guid>
      <description>:CUSTOM_ID: average-true-range-atr
The ATR is a very important indicator in this system that is used - amongst other functions - for money management.
ATR
The ATR is the only pre-defined indicator in the NNFX algo.
Instead of the ATR, Standard deviation could also be used for money / risk management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combination of Indicators</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/combination-of-indicators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/combination-of-indicators/</guid>
      <description>:CUSTOM_ID: combining :ID: 5db8c230-8ac7-4564-a544-fd0d4372523c
The resulting metric for combined indicators must be larger than the metric for each individual indicator or indicator sub-sets.
This ensures that adding a single indicator to the set actually is beneficial.
Implications Indicators may not be compatible :PROPERTIES: :CUSTOM_ID: indicators-may-not-be-compatible :END: Good individual results may be bad in combination with other indicators.
Bad individual results may lead to good results when combined Bad individual results must not be fully eliminated but when selecting a candidate for combining with other indicators a weighted selection process should be applied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hit Miss Ratio</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/hit-miss-ratio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/hit-miss-ratio/</guid>
      <description>Definition The hit miss ratio Metric is defined by VP in Backtesting Step-by-step as win-rate.
This metric indicates if right after the entry signal price moves in our direction before it moves the other way.
We use the terminology hit/miss instead of win/loss.
 Here is what determines a win [hit] or a loss [miss], listen up.
 – Start from today, and go back in time until you see your indicator give a buy or sell signal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indicator Function</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/indicator-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/indicator-function/</guid>
      <description>:CUSTOM_ID: indicator-function
The indicator function or simply function (func) defines the purpose of an indicator within an indicator set.
An indicator contains indicators with the following functions:
 Confirmation (C1)    2nd Confirmation Indicator (C2) 3rd Confirmation (C3)    Volume or Valatility Indicator (V)    Baseline (B)    Exit (E)    Average True Range (ATR)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indicator Selection</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/indicator-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/indicator-selection/</guid>
      <description>:CUSTOM_ID: indicator-selection
Indicator selection describes the procedure and criteria of selecting multiple sliced indicator sets from a pool of available configurations for combination and further testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indicator Set</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/indicator-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/indicator-set/</guid>
      <description>:CUSTOM_ID: indicator-set
An indicator set (indi set) is a set of indicators used in a - so called - algorithm. Each indicator has a specific indicator function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indicator Side</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/20200820171402-side/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/20200820171402-side/</guid>
      <description>Indicator Side At any given time an indicator has a side that indicates long, short or neutral.
Typically if the last signal was a long signal the side of this indicator is long until the indicator gives a signal in the oposite direction. Same for short signals.
Some indicators also describe a neutral state.
Examples With a Two Lines Cross indicator with an up and a down line, the side is simply which line has the higher value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indicators</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/indicator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/indicator/</guid>
      <description>:ID: 230500d7-fbef-458d-9e60-f7bf5bc086ae
An indicator contains a specific mathematical function based on historical data and tries to predict future price movements.
At certain points the indicator gives a signal which indicates to buy/sell at a specific point of time and at a specific price level.
Each Indicator has various input parameters which change the behavior of the indicator. For example an input parameter of a moving average indicator will be the period on which the moving average is calculated&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Input Parameters</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/input-parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/input-parameters/</guid>
      <description>usually referred to as input.
Types of Input Parameters An MT5 Indicator may have different types of inputs
 Integer Float String Boolean (Bool) Enumerations (Enum)  Continuous Input An input is continuous if an adjacent input value only slightly changes the function of an indicator.
Adjacent input values result in a continuous result space.
Typically Integer and Float inputs are continuous.
An example would be the the period of an moving average.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K-Ratio</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/k-ratio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/k-ratio/</guid>
      <description>Kestner (2003)
 The K-Ratio is a statistical metric with an emphasis on consistency of returns, introduced by Lars Kestner in 1996 [1]. It has since then also been adapted by Zephyr Associates under the name &amp;ldquo;Zephyr K-Ratio&amp;rdquo; [2]. Having multiple different Equity curves, yielding the same amount of profit, the K-Ratio will prefer the curve with the most consistent gains (maximum smoothness).
Naturally, most investors also prefer a smooth equity curve over higher profits with deeper drawdowns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metrics</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/metrics/</guid>
      <description>:CUSTOM_ID: metrics
A metric or also called a fitness function in this system describes a function to evaluate the performance of an indicator or an Indicator Set.
Metrics:
 Hit Miss Ratio    Profit Factor (PF)    K-Ratio  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimization Procedure</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/optimization-procedure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/optimization-procedure/</guid>
      <description>The optimization procedure in this system defines the process of finding a profitable configuration for the system according to the given algortihm rules.
TODO Backtesting in Metatrader 5 New Indicators The optimization starts with adding and testing new indicators to calculate the metric for a range of Input Parameters. In order to filter (reduce) the result for further processing we analyze the results. The resulting configurations is referred to as Sliced Indicator Set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parameter Optimization</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/parameter-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/parameter-optimization/</guid>
      <description>Developing &amp;amp; Backtesting Systematic Trading Strategies (pdf)
Peterson, Brian. (2017). Developing &amp;amp; Backtesting Systematic Trading Strategies.
 Parameter optimization is important for indicators, signals, rules, and complete trading systems. Care needs to be taken to do this as safely as possible. That care needs to start with clearly defined objectives, as has already been stated. The goal of parameter optimization shouldbe to locate a parameter combination that most closely matches thehypotheses and objectives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profit Factor</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/profit-factor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/profit-factor/</guid>
      <description>It is the ratio between Gross profits and Gross losses.
Interpreting a Strategy Performance Report explains it as
 The profit factor is defined as the gross profit divided by the gross loss (including commissions) for the entire trading period. This performance metric relates the amount of profit per unit of risk, with values greater than one indicating a profitable system. [&amp;hellip;] We all know that not every trade will be a winner and that we will have to sustain losses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Indicator</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/20200820135757-random_indicator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/20200820135757-random_indicator/</guid>
      <description>The random indicator is an indicator that randomly takes trades in any direction. This can be considered the baseline which we have to surpass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the result set</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/reducing-the-result-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/reducing-the-result-set/</guid>
      <description>Reducing n n is the number of values of a single input parameter. /The lengths of the input sets are obviously not all the same but for O() notation this does not matter./
The size of n is defined by the number of possible values. The range, describing this has a start, a stop and a step value.
 If we reduce the move start and stop closer together. In case of a continuous input parameter the step value can be increased.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signal</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/signal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/signal/</guid>
      <description>A signal is the event produces by an Indicator that indicates entering or exiting a trade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sliced Indicator Set</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/sliced-indicator-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/sliced-indicator-set/</guid>
      <description>also called segmented.
The output of the analyzing results stage that reduces the result set. A sliced indicator set has ranged input parameters because working with ranged inputs is significantly more efficient than with</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standard Deviation</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/20200820155536-standard_deviation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/20200820155536-standard_deviation/</guid>
      <description>Instead of the ATR Standard deviation could also be used for money / risk management.
TODO there was a post describing the similarities of the ATR and standard deviation. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Profit</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/20200820135056-tp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/20200820135056-tp/</guid>
      <description>Definition at Babypips
In this system, a take profit {TP} is set at \(Entry + ATR\) 1
  for long trades and Entry - ATR for short trades &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing New Indicators</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/testing-new-indicators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/testing-new-indicators/</guid>
      <description>After a new indicator is defined in the system it shall be tested. Testing means calculating the fitness function (metric) for each input parameter set.
The current implementation plan is to process all possible input parameters. This has \(O(n^m)\). \(n\) possible values per input. \(m\) different free inputs.
If an indicator has 10k input parameter and it is combined with another indicator of also 10k inputs the resulting search space is \(10k^2 = 100M\)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VP</title>
      <link>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/vp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stfl.github.io/backtestd-doc/articles/vp/</guid>
      <description>:CUSTOM_ID: vp
VP 1 is the creator of No Nonsense Forex
  real name unknown &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>